hey guys welcome back to my channel
today i'm going to show you how to
create these beautiful fluffy brows as
you can see my natural brows aren't
quite as full and fluffy they're not
super sparse but they're not super full
leaver so this is a great way to cheat a
fluffy brow without having to go through
microblading so i'm going to start with
the anastasia beverly hills brow freeze
and i would say this is kind of like a
hybrid between a wax and a gel as you
can see it is completely translucent and
it's specifically been designed to
create a feathery eyebrow which you
would ordinarily use soap for
so i like to take a little spatula and
decant a small amount a little goes a
long way and if you use too much then
the brow becomes heavy and it won't kind
of stay in place but if you don't use
enough again then it won't stay in place
it's kind of trial and error i'm taking
a spoolie brush and i like to bend it as
this makes brushing the hairs a little
bit easier at that angle rather than
straight and then all you do is swipe
one side of your brush into the brow wax
to really coat all the bristles
make sure your eyebrow hair is clean of
any oils and then start by combing your
brows in the opposite direction is not
the most flattering finish but you want
to coat the hairs both sides
only once you've coated both sides can
you start combing the hairs upwards and
i promise you it will make the world of
difference to the way your brows lay and
the amount they stay in place
another tip for this method is to be
patient so keep combing because the more
you comb them the more they're going to
listen to what you want them to do and
that sounds really random it's a bit
like changing the parting on your hair
if you flip it over it doesn't
ordinarily lay that way so the hair
doesn't automatically want to lay flat
so what we're doing is taming the hair
and this can take a few goes to really
get it to lay flat you might also want
to use your finger to press the hair
down and then just give it a little comb
over and then we're starting to get a
really good starting point for the
fluffy eyebrows
the front brows are going to be going up
at a slight angle and the hairs towards
the back are just going outwards so we
are getting more of a fluffy look now if
you don't have an artistic eye you might
not see the natural guide that we have
going on here so i've just pointed it
out with a little diagram just to show
you that this is the shape that we're
going to be filling in so if you have
particularly coarse hair or super long
hair and it falls outside the guide then
you might want to trim those hairs but
only the stragglers you don't want to
trim it all because we want that fluffy
finish my two favorite brow pens are the
urban decay brow blade and the mac shape
and shade brow tin however there are an
abundance of different pens out there
these are just my favorite because they
have a tiny tiny tip today i'm using the
mac shape and shade brow tin in the
shade fling which is like a dirty blonde
and i like to start at the front of the
eyebrow a lot of people like to start at
the back half whichever suits you i find
that i like to use a lighter hand at the
very front and then i can get fuller as
we get towards the back of the brow i
like to start the very base and flick
upwards as i work my way along i'm
starting to see the shape that i want to
create a tip is to use a super light
hand when you do this because you want
the very end of the flick to be light so
it looks like a hair once i've done the
base all the way up to where the arches
i then like to start flicking the hair
at the front upwards to create the top
half of the shape again this needs to be
really light because the front of the
eyebrow is the most sparse so that's why
i'm creating more hair strokes there and
then i'm just adding small strokes in
the outer half of the brow along the top
where it's most fast but you'll find
this particular area needs less work
than the front because it is fuller than
that front area you'll want to change
the direction of your flicks as we get
towards the arch and the tail of the
eyebrow just follow that natural
direction that you've brushed the hairs
i personally like to add a little bit
more definition to the tail just so it
comes down to a bit more of a point for
me that makes it look more defined i
want the brass look fluffy but i don't
want them to look scruffy so this is a
before and after in a sense because you
can see one brow that looks nice and
full and fluffy and the brow that
doesn't
i've tried the brow freeze a number of
times and i do find that it doesn't hold
up as well on my brows so i personally
like to set the final result in place
with the benefit 24 hour brow setter in
clear
this one stays in place until i take it
off it wouldn't be as good at holding my
brows up in this position on its own
without the brow freeze but the
combination of the two for me work
perfectly so i'm going to recreate the
same look on my second brow i'm going to
allow you to watch it and then i'm going
to come back at the end
[Music]
do
so as you can see that is both eyebrows
full and fluffy they don't look over the
top and obviously this is up close but
from a distance they do look super hairy
and very very natural
and you can see from the before and
afters that it is quite a transformation
and brows really do frame the face
however if this all feels a bit too
technical for you or a bit too artistic
then i have plenty of other brow
tutorials for a natural finish using
both pencils and powders as well as pens
so if you are interested in trying an
alternative method to achieve more
natural full looking brows but without
it being too artistic i will link them
on screen for you now and i'm just
putting up a couple of extra examples of
the different tutorials that i have
created
i'm always on the lookout to try new eye
pens because i feel like they give you
the most natural finish so if there are
any that you've tried that i haven't
mentioned then i would be really
intrigued to learn more about them i
have seen that there's one by nyx that
i've not tried if you've tried it what
did you think let me know in the comment
section
so anyway as always guys thank you so
much for watching please give the
tutorial a thumbs up if you enjoyed it
if you've got any questions leave them
in the comment section below and i'll do
my best to get back to you
thank you so much for watching don't
forget to follow me outside of youtube
on my social handles which will be on
screen for you now and i will see you
next week bye